



# **Gustavo Santos**

O Home: 2800-058, Almada, Portugal

**Email:** g henrique19@hotmail.com **Phone:** (+351) 937524422

Date of birth: 24/07/1990 Nationality: Brazilian

#### **ABOUT ME**

In the IT area I have been working on projects with Java on the backend and Angular2+ on the Frontend, as my main language at the moment I am focusing on specializing in Java Web development.

I have a strong sense of problem solving, flexibility, teamwork, autonomy to work without assistance.

Visit my repository on Github, contains the knowledge I am acquiring in IT: https:// github.com/ghrs123

#### **DIGITAL SKILLS**

Ease of Learning New Software | good communication and teamwork skills | Administration of Computer networks | Java | Hibernate | JDBC - JPA | Spring Boot | Maven | Junit, Mockito | Docker / Docker Compose | SQL (MySQL, SQL Server) | C, HTML, CSS, Java script, Java, PHP, SQL, Bootstrap | Angular | TypeScript | Jenkins | Uipath | VCS (Git, SVN) | Scrum Methodology | Agile Methodologies | Robotics Process Automation (RPA) | Linux

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

[ 10/2022 - Current ] Java Developer

#### **Quantico Solutions**

City: Lisbon

**Country:** Portugal

#### Adp Valor - Águas de Portugal

- -Corrective and evolutionary maintenance in frontend and backend
- -Tasks managment

Technologies used: Angular14, Quakus, Azure, MySql database

### **Ministry of Education - Registration Portal**

- Development of new Features
- Corrective and Evolutionary Maintenance

Technologies used: Angular 10, Thorntail framework (microservices - just maintenance), Jira, GitLab, Oracle Database, Microprofile, Jenkins(just to generate images), Rancher(Kubernet menager - just deploy)

#### **DGE** - Directorate-General for Education

- Corrective and Evolutionary Maintenance
- Responsible for the analysis of the application of the new features

Technologies used: GitLab, SpringBoot(api's), spring MVC and Thymeleaf for front, SpringSecurity, Oracle Database, Jira

# [ 09/2022 – Current ] **Java Developer**

#### **Lorius Solutions**

City: Bruxells Country: Belgium

Development application of ticket management

Tasks carried out:

- Creation of RE model
- ER Diagram
- Database creation (mysql)
- Back-end and front-end application structuring
- Back-end and front-end development

Technologies used: Spring Boot, Spring Data JPA, Spring Security, Angular, MySQL, CI/ CD, REST, Angular, Swagger, gitLab, Jira, JUnit

# [ 02/2022 – 10/2022 ] **Junior Java Developer**

# CGI Portugal

City: Lisbon

**Country:** Portugal

#### Development of internal application for curriculum management and employee information.

Tasks performed by:

- Survey of requirements, documentation and model of the application
- Creation of the ER (drawio) template
- ER diagram (mysql)
- Creation of databases (mysql)
- Back-end structuring following the repository pattern
- Development of the back-end
- Front-end development in Angular

Technologies used: Spring Boot, Spring Data JPA, HTML, CSS, bootstrap, Angular, Github, mysql

#### **ANSR- National Road Safety Authority**

Responsible for the documentation of webservices integrated to the system used by ANSR as, SIGA.

Tasks performed by:

- Versioning with SVN
- Tests on soapUI
- Data management in SQL Server
- Creation of macros in VBA
- Creation of data dictionary

# [ 07/2021 - 10/2021 ] Internship RPA Uipath Developer

#### CGI Portugal

City: Lisbon

Country: Portugal

- PDD document creation
- Robot development
- Functional tests

# [ 09/2021 - 12/2021 ] **RPA Developer**

# CGI Portugal

City: Lisboa

Country: Portugal

**BPI** bank

- Analysis, Project Development, RPA's Automation Tests applied to multiple systems.
- Maintenance and application improvement
- Good practice
- Monitoring logs

### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

[09/2023 - 12/2023]

# Intersive English couse, Second Language Learning

International House Malta https://www.ihmalta.com/en/

City: St Julians **Country:** Malta

[ 05/2020 - 29/07/2021 ]

# **Specialist in Information Systems Technologies and Programming**

ATEC https://www.atec.pt/academia-formacao-atec/contactos-palmela.html

Address: Quinta da Marqueza, 2950-557, Palmela, Portugal

[02/2012 - 11/2017]

# **Mechanical Engineering**

FHO - Uniararas http://fho.edu.br/

Address: Av. Dr. Maximiliano Baruto, Jd. Universitário, 500, 13607-339, Araras SP, Brazil

[01/2012 - 04/2012]

# **Programming and Operation of CNC lathe**

SENAI https://araras.sp.senai.br/

Address: Av. Ignacio Zurita Neto, 1025 - Jardim das Flores,, 13607-207, Araras, Brazil

[12/2010 - 12/2011]

## **Machining Mechanic on Conventional Machines**

**SENAI** https://araras.sp.senai.br/

Address: Av. Ignacio Zurita Neto, 1025 - Jardim das Flores, 13607-207, Araras, Brazil

[05/2010 - 11/2010]

# **Administrative Techniques and Organisational Behaviour**

http://www.aehda.org.br/ **AEHDA** 

Address: Av. Renata C. Prado, 185 - Jardim Belvedere, 13601-123, Araras, Brazil

[12/2008 - 11/2009]

## **Personal Development**

**AEHDA** http://www.aehda.org.br/

Address: Av. Ignacio Zurita Neto, 1025 - Jardim das Flores, 13601-123, Araras, Brazil

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

[11/2023 - 11/2023] Spring Security 6 Zero to Master along with JWT, OAUTH2

OpenID Connect

OAUTH2

Keycloak

JSON Web Token (JWT)

..

Link: https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-3096ee96-771b-4336-b3cc-82c9b2cd8f66/

## [ 08/2023 - 08/2023 ] **DOCKER Complete - From Scratch to Advanced (2023)**

Docker

Docker-compose

Linux

Credential ID: UC-af413be7-9d07-4e16-8f03-6d22e0cf0c92

Link: https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-af413be7-9d07-4e16-8f03-6d22e0cf0c92/

### [ 07/2023 - 07/2023 ] RESTful API with Spring Boot and Java 8 - Reference Guide

Spring Framework

Travis CI

Flyway

EhCache

lava

Credential ID: UC-be513bdf-376e-488d-85cf-f7d7b979b3c1

Link: https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-be513bdf-376e-488d-85cf-f7d7b979b3c1/

### [ 04/2023 - 04/2023 ] Unit tests in JAVA: Master JUnit, Mockito and TDD

Coverage Analysis

**DataBuilders** 

JUnit

Mockery

PowerMock

lava

Credential ID: UC-6439a8cf-adab-40c0-8b21-6eaa0a786fab

Link: https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-6439a8cf-adab-40c0-8b21-6eaa0a786fab/

#### **LANGUAGE SKILLS**

Mother tongue(s): Portuguese Sign Language

Other language(s):

**English** 

LISTENING B1 READING B1 WRITING B1

**SPOKEN PRODUCTION B1 SPOKEN INTERACTION B1** 

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user